I want you to be alive
after your entire family is dead.
That is what will hurt you the most.
Michael is badly wounded.
John is dead.
I sent a message to Aberama Gold.
I need you back.
I'll help you
'cause Michael wants me to help you.
Starting now.
The bullet's been written.
Me, as the oldest brother,
will put this bullet into his head.
You said you'd bring
every man and woman out on strike.
Do you have a whistle?
It's almost
as if you want trouble.
All right,
first come, first served.
Form an orderly line, all of you.
All right. All right.
Right!
Have your contracts of employment
in your hand!
Bring 'em in. Get in there.
Get moving.
On you go. Go on.
Keep going. Keep going.
You, where are you going?
- Bradley. Foreman.
- All right.
You go and see that man over there. Go.
- What's your name?
- Bradley. I'm the foreman.
- When did you last work here?
- 1922.
How many have done
this type of work before?
They're mostly farm hands
from down Worcester way.
But I'll show 'em.
Hungry men learn fast.
All right. On you go.
Dirty scabs! Black legs!
What bastard threw that?
Get him out here!
Bring him out!
It wasn't me!
Arthur!
Oi! Enough.
Come on. Get him out. Get out!
Get out!
All right, ten more.
Two more.
- That's it.
- Ten.
Close it up.
Right. Ten bob a man.
Two pound there for you.
What about security?
Yeah, well about that.
By order of the city of Birmingham
police department,
you and your ugly workforce
are now under the protection
of the Peaky fucking Blinders.
- Mr Gray?
- Yeah, send him in.
It's your mother.
Oh, fuck.
I read about it in the paper.
I have a right.
I'm your mum as well.
You want me to go away?
Yes.
I'll just leave these.
They're from our orchard.
You used to love these.
I hope there are no worms in them.
Look,
I just wanted to say
that you're welcome to come home.
To get better at home.
I know you got bored
in the village but...
we love you.
And your little brother
misses playing football with you.
And your dad...
passed on.
He passed on peacefully in our bed.
Oh, fuck.
Now go home.
I'm expecting Tommy.
He's due here now.
I'll go then.
I'll not be in the same room
as that man.
Come on, Poll, Tommy's expecting us.
Who's with us?
Isiah and two Lee boys.
Ada? How long since you've had a fuck?
What?
Been nearly two years with me.
Over Christmas, I counted it up.
So I've made a New Year's resolution
to change the situation.
Oh. Anyone particular in mind?
Not really.
Just me and someone unsuitable.
# From starry eyes colliding
# From Mars to someone crying
I'll sit in the front.
# No matter what I'm hiding
# I get lost
# But I always come around
# Call when you're ready
'cause I'm ready to ride #
So this is just to make
business official.
Your official return
to the company payroll.
So no more talk
of New Year's resolutions
or Tommy might change his mind.
What New Year's resolutions?
Never mind.
I think Ada's trying to
tell me to behave myself.
Yeah. Behave yourself.
Behave myself or what?
Behave myself or fucking what?
Okay Polly, I'll tell you the truth.
After your recent troubles,
Tommy asked me to keep an eye on you.
Troubles?
Whilst working for this company
I have killed a man,
I have lost a man, I have found a son,
I have nearly lost a son,
I have nearly lost my own life.
Now I will accept my job back
if the terms on offer are favourable.
But I will not behave myself.
Sorry I'm late.
Where's Arthur?
Do I look like his fucking mother?
No, Linda.
Why are you here?
You all right? Is Billy all right?
Yes. Everything's fine.
Well look, lovely to see you,
but I'm late for a meeting.
They can wait.
I've got something for you.
Something for a loving husband
who's been working very hard
and is under a great deal of pressure.
Something to relieve his stress
Oh.
It's silk. From Japan.
Feel.
My hands are dirty.
Good.
Feel all of it.
Feel it properly.
You, uh, you want to do this here?
Why not? I thought you were the boss.
I am the fucking boss.
So tell me what to do, boss.
Come here.
Right.
Before we start
this extraordinary general meeting
of the board
of the Shelby Company Limited,
I'd like to note the absence
of the Deputy Vice President
who has not yet arrived.
We will continue without his presence.
Item number one.
The reinstatement
of the Shelby Company Limited
Company Treasurer.
The board welcomes back
the former treasurer,
with generously improved
terms and conditions.
Due to the exceptionally
difficult circumstances
the company now finds itself in.
The proposed treasurer
will now check the terms and conditions
to see if they are in order.
Item number two.
During the absence of the
Company Accountant, due to ill health,
all responsibility for
the keeping of company accounts
pass to the head of acquisitions.
Item number three.
The Company Treasurer,
having read the terms and condition,
lodges a signed contract of employment
agreeing to the terms and conditions
with the temporary head of accounts.
All those in favour of the reinstatement
of Mrs Elizabeth Gray,
to the position of Shelby Company
Limited Company Treasurer,
please raise your hands.
Why goodness, thank you.
Any other business?
Right. I declare this extraordinary
general meeting over.
Now we can talk about the real business.
But for that we need Arthur.
Where the fuck is Arthur?
- Mr Shelby...
- Fuck off.
- They've broken into the paint shop.
- Oh, yeah?
They're chucking paint around.
I think they mean to set light to it.
Well, you deal with it, man.
I'm fucking busy!
What was all that about?
In this sinful place
there will be temptations.
It's my responsibility as your wife
to help you resist those temptations.
By putting myself between you...
and the devil.
In the words
of my sinful Catholic mother,
"Keep his balls empty
and his belly full."
God rest her soul.
Mr Shelby...
You have to come
to the paint shop immediately. Please.
I have to go.
Won't be late.
Sorry, ladies,
there's no smoking in here.
Yes, love, we know.
All right, he's an hour late.
Fuck him.
This business directly affects Arthur,
but he's not here,
so we'll take a vote without him.
What business?
Official business that wasn't
on your agenda, Ada.
An informant told us
that six years ago, Luca Changretta
came from New York to Birmingham
to be best man at his cousin's wedding.
We found out that they used
Reid and Dunn on Broadgate
for the photographs.
The photographer kept the negatives.
I persuaded him to give us copies.
And to enlarge this one.
That is Luca Changretta.
I've seen his face,
so I could pick him out.
Half the men in the photograph
are Changrettas,
which means the chances are
they are the men who come to kill us.
We need to get both these photographs
into pubs and on street corners.
Then we put it about
that there's a reward for information.
We also propose that we give a copy
of this photograph to Mr Aberama Gold.
We need to forget the idea that it
has to be Arthur that pulls the trigger.
Tradition will just fuck us up.
We should wait for Arthur.
Arthur's not here, Ada.
We need Luca Changretta dead. That's it.
Dropping the law of the bullet
is part of the process of modernisation
that I was working on before I...
Before I was executed.
You weren't executed, Poll.
What did you call me?
Right. Let's take a vote.
I'll deal with Arthur.
All those in favour
of giving the photographs to Mr Gold,
raise your hand.
Then it will be done.
- Mum...
- Oh, "Mum" now, is it?
I smelt perfume when I came in here.
Yeah, it was the flowers.
Right, that's it.
Who came in here, Michael?
The truth is, Polly,
the woman that raised him came in here.
She has every right to come in here.
She brought him fucking apples
and she left.
We are in the middle
of a vendetta and Arthur is missing.
We need to find him.
Concentrate on what unites us.
- This is all temporary.
- Yeah, temporary. Right.
# There's a devil inside of me
# He's holding on... #
Bastards!
# And I don't know if he's staying
# Or for how long
# There's a devil inside of me.
# And he's holding on
# And I don't know if he's staying
or for how long... #
Party is it, eh?
Is that what it is?
What is this, a party, eh?
Fuck off out of it! Get out!
# And I'm sad to say
he's got me thinking
# About the bad parts of my life...
Okay, I wasn't gonna hit ya.
But that wasn't fucking nice.
# There's a devil inside of me
A monolith of doom
Oh, you...
Arthur... Mr Shelby, please.
- Please.
- Don't fucking move.
- Eh?
- Mr Shelby, please, please, please.
Now get the fuck out!
Fuck your fuckin' revolution!
# I find I'm right back at the start #
I'm a fucking mess.
Shh.
Where are you going?
Come here.
Fucking hit man, are you?
Eh? Is that what you are?
Arthur Shelby, eh?
Let's see who wanted you.
What about...
What about fucking John Shelby?
Huh?
John.
Thank you.
Send my guests in.
You wire Polo
and let him tell the family.
He has four kids.
Don't you two have
any other clothes to wear?
Huh?
Look at me.
I'm here as a lover of theatre.
They kill two of our men...
You complain about your fucking belly.
Luca.
- With respect.
- "With respect"?
You raised...
"With respect"?
Open your mouth.
- Come on...
- Open your fucking mouth!
You fucking dress like them.
You eat like them.
You don't fucking talk to me
about, "With respect".
Sit down.
What do you have?
Arthur Shelby killed her son
in a boxing ring four years ago.
She would do that for us?
Okay.
Anyone seen Arthur?
Anyone seen Arthur? Eh?
In your office, Tom.
If you're not going to show up
for a family meeting,
let someone know.
We thought you were dead.
There's 15 fucking Italians out there.
No there's not, there's 13.
I just killed two of them.
Ripped out their hearts
and burnt their bones to ash.
I did it.
Me.
Your brother.
Not fucking Aberama Gold
or his punch drunk son.
But me.
Even if you don't trust me no more.
What the fuck are you talking about?
Arthur?
I got cleaned up at Ada's.
She told me.
You took a vote in my absence.
All right, calm down
and tell me about the men you killed.
You put my job out for contract.
Arthur...
Yeah, well, I'm gonna make it
my fucking job anyway.
Because this was all my fault.
It was me that shot the old man.
- Yeah, out of mercy.
- Aye.
NowJohn's dead.
He's dead because of me
and I'm gonna make it right.
Arthur, wait.
How did the men get in the factory?
I need to know.
Through the back fucking door
that was supposed to be
locked and bolted.
Some bastard gave me up.
Somebody with keys.
Yeah. Why don't you sit down
and work it out for yourself.
Take a fucking vote.
Who is this little bear?
Yes. Eh?
Are you all right?
Daddy's home, isn't he?
Yeah, I'm all right.
Look, Daddy's home.
How's Polly?
Is she all right?
Oh, go on, Linda.
I mean, it was her idea,
wasn't it? Hmm?
The Japanese silk? Hmm?
I'll put him to bed.
You kept me away from that
fucking meeting to stop me from voting.
- Here we go.
- It was Polly's idea, wasn't it?
Eh?
You know what I am, don't ya?
I'm a working man. Yeah.
Fucking working man.
Fucking...
Who's lost his job.
Is that what I am, Linda?
Is that what I am, eh?
I don't want you dead.
Polly doesn't want you dead.
Let Mr Gold do the killing for money.
It's the modern way, Arthur.
Watch.
Hmm? Hmm?
What are you doing?
Now fire it into the fireplace.
Please.
- All right.
- Fire it.
Get rid of it.
Then we'll go to bed.
We'll do anything you like.
Just fire the gun, Arthur.
Fire it.
Ah!
You go tell Polly...
there are rules between a man and woman.
There are rules.
That I have to do this.
I have to do it.
John wants me to do it, Linda.
My brother...
And I'm gonna do it!
Was it fear or was it hatred?
Was what fear or hatred?
Isiah...
You had a one way ticket to Glasgow
in your pocket.
Your wife and kids left three days ago.
Now, I'm gonna ask you again.
Was it fear of the Italians
or hatred of us
that made you unlock the door
and give up my brother?
I didn't unlock any door.
Here, have a drink.
You're gonna need it.
Thirty five Drumcree Street,
Parkhead, Glasgow...
Please, please, please, please...
We have allegiances
with Catholic gangs in that city.
Your family are safe
only at my discretion.
Now, explain to me why you were
catching the midnight train to Glasgow.
You mean you don't know?
I run a factory
full of black leg non-union labour.
I live in a street
full of men laid off or on strike.
Look at the photograph, Mr Devlin,
and tell me who are the men
- that contacted you.
- No.
No, you listen to me.
I get spat at, windows smashed,
petrol on the curtains.
But for fear of you
I clock in every fucking morning.
And today, two men are shot
and burnt on my shift.
And you ask me why I'm getting on
the midnight train to Glasgow.
Who else has the keys to that door?
They hang on a hook inside my office.
Today I left the office unlocked.
- Why?
- Because I forgot.
Because I left in a hurry.
Because there were men
trying to set fire to the factory.
Mr Shelby, may I tell you something?
You have a lot of enemies.
Communists. Italians.
Before the factory came out on strike,
I heard word that two Italians attended
a communist party meeting in Stechford.
They hardly spoke English.
Now, if they got a party man
into the factory,
it might have been him
that unlocked the door for them.
Mr Shelby, my train leaves at 12:00.
It's just gone 11:00.
I can still make it.
Please. For my kids.
I need you here.
Isiah, get three of our men
with police badges
to watch Mr Devlin's house.
Mr Shelby, please...
Our friends in Glasgow
will take care of your family.
For the curtains.
Before you, I was
an ordinary working man.
Yeah, and now you're one of us.
# Blackbird, blackbird
Singing the blues all day
# Right outside of my door... #
- Who is it?
- Tommy Shelby.
- Is this union business?
- Yes.
So conduct it in the proper place
at the proper time.
I've come to make an improved offer.
I heard music.
What's your improved offer?
- Do I not get a drink?
- No.
Have you ever seen any of the men
in this photograph before?
What?
You're a member
of the Stechford Communist party.
I'm told two Italian men
attended a meeting recently.
Can you see either of the men
in this picture?
As the Small Heath coordinator
of the Organisation
for the Maintenance of Supplies
I have also been sworn in
as a Special...
We have reason to believe
that outside agitators from overseas
are attempting to foment trouble
in our factories
in advance of a General Strike
which could take place at any moment.
This is a matter of national security.
May I look at your badge?
Yes.
What would you like to drink, Constable?
Whisky.
And, actually, it's Sergeant.
I only have beer. Times are hard.
How long has it been since you've had
a bottle of M&B bitter?
Help yourself.
Have a seat.
You know, when this business began,
I did some research on you.
It turns out I know someone
who used to know you very well.
KittyJurossi.
You were in love with Kitty's sister.
Greta Jurossi. Before the war.
Do you remember Greta Jurossi?
Her parents were Italian.
They didn't approve of a Watery Lane
Gypsy, but you won them over.
With your charm. Sweetness.
Very, very thorough research.
Greta died at the age of 19.
Of consumption.
And Kitty said you were at her bedside
for three months.
Every day, holding her hand.
And after she died you went away to war.
Kitty said that the sweet boy who left
never came back.
No one came back.
Here's the funniest thing.
She said in those days
you believed in things.
In justice. Fairness.
Once you saw a man beating his horse
and you fought him.
He was twice your size but you beat him.
And then you beat him with his own whip.
Kitty always liked to tell tall tales.
She's a party member now.
She swears
before you enlisted in the army
you joined the Communist party yourself.
Is that true?
You know, when I was at the door,
I saw you through the curtains.
You were dancing alone.
I've also done my research.
Your sweetheart was at Passchendaele.
When he came back,
he was listed among the shell shocked.
Blew his own fucking brains out.
I don't know any men in the photo.
You haven't looked.
This afternoon two men came into
my factory and tried to kill my brother.
I believe a Stechford Communist party
member let him in.
I was wondering if you might be able
to help me in my investigations.
Kitty said next time I see you,
before we start fighting,
I should send you her love
from the good old days
and give you this.
Greta Jurossi and Tommy Shelby
in Blackpool.
Do you recognise the boy
in the photograph?
I'll leave that here.
Apologies for interrupting your dance.
# I wish
# I wait
# But it's all in vain
# I wish I was a maid again
# But a maid again
# I never can be
# Till apples grow... #
Arthur... I need you to listen to me.
I need you to listen to me, Arthur...
The world is changing.
Listen to me, Arthur.
And listen to the sweet voice
ofJesus...
# I wish... #
- Finn?
- It came from Arthur's house.
Arthur.
Where is he?
He fired the bullet.
Linda...
Said it's the modern way, Tom...
It's the modern way.
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, it's all right.
It's all right, brother.
You did well.
God spoke to him, not me.
What are you doing here?
On Mondays, I do the inventory.
Make sure nobody's dipping their hand.
Well, it's my job now.
I'm back.
And there's gonna be nobody
dipping their hand with me here,
not unless they want it cut off.
I said to Arthur
while I'm stuck in this fucking place
I want something to keep my mind busy.
What? You're going to take bets?
I have always been able to do addition
and subtraction without pen and paper.
But I'll need a telephone.
Apparently we have special clients
who take bets by telephone.
Linda?
This is a betting shop.
Look.
Arthur said yes. Tommy said yes.
But did God say yes?
Gambling is a sin, Linda.
It's not me that's doing the gambling.
I'm just taking the bets.
The rule is that door should always
remain locked until 9:00 A. M.
Right. Boy. Boy, where are you going?
Well, Arthur's not coming in today.
He's taking the day off. So...
So what?
So today, Tommy said that I'm in charge.
Sorry, you're in charge?
Yeah. That's what he said.
All right, sweetheart.
Ladies?
Let's give our boss a first day
that he'll never forget.
Sending Finn to the shop was a mistake.
They've already found out
he's a virgin
and they're arranging a girl for him,
this afternoon.
I thought Linda was there.
She is. She loved the idea.
I know. She even swears now.
"Fuck".
Sounds funny coming from her.
Polly says in the end
we all turn into our mother.
Well, keep an eye on her.
Hmm.
The whore watching the Madonna.
Does Finn know what they have planned?
No.
Do they have someone?
Yes. A girl I used to work with.
- Is she nice?
- No.
She's from Aston.
They're paying her out of petty cash.
Right, well, call 'em
and tell them to pay extra
and get someone nice.
Nice women don't do that sort of thing.
Yes, they do. What about you?
I mean in the past. Come on.
Where are we going?
Somewhere I've not been in a long time.
Are we expecting somebody?
Tommy, I'm fucking freezing here.
We used to come here.
She'd wait for hours for me,
when I couldn't make it.
And I'd wait for her
if her family kept her in.
Who?
Some girl.
Some girl before France.
I've not been back here since.
But I wanted to come here with you.
Are you kissing her or me?
You.
I want Shelby Company Limited
to increase non-taxable
charitable contributions
to local charities
by twenty-five percent
as of now.
And I'm gonna build
two new institutes
for destitute children.
One in Saltley, one in Digbeth.
I've already identified the buildings.
Two former workhouses.
I want you to be
in charge of the project.
All right, come on, let's go.
Why?
Because I promised someone
I'd change the world.
You do realise, Tommy,
we're all going fucking mad here.
Yeah, I know.
Come on.
Finn? Come here.
- How was your day?
- Yeah, it was okay.
Good man. Well done.
No trouble?
No. No trouble.
And she looked after you?
I don't want it like that
ever again, Tom.
Not when they don't even want to do it,
except for the money.
Everything's for the money, Finn.
Yeah, I know. But...
She said, "Be a man."
And were you a man?
Yeah.
But then I apologised to her.
Because she looked so tired.
Sit down, Finn.
Right, listen to me, Finn.
She was right.
You need to be a fucking man.
People get tired.
Working in a fucking factory
gets you tired.
I don't go round apologising.
Do I?
No.
There's an empty space here
to be filled.
Do you understand?
- Yeah.
- So...
Be a fucking man.
Okay, Tom.
- Champagne, please.
- Of course.
Madam...
Women alone are not allowed at the bar.
Will someone be joining you?
What do you think?
This is public enough, no?
Yes.
So?
The boy in the hospital
is out of bounds.
And I will ask you
to spare Finn and Arthur.
In return for what?
Tommy Shelby.
And, uh, why should I trust you?
Because you know our history.
You know what happened between us.
You are an unlikely Cassius.
Mmm...
You know, my mother...
My mother knew your mother.
She taught her how to read.
Did she tell you
that John and Arthur spared her life?
When Tommy wanted her dead.
Yeah.
And now she's given me
the information about you people.
So Tommy Shelby was right.
His, uh, ruthlessness
was justified.
You should have killed her
when you had the chance.
John was a good boy.
Arthur tries.
Tommy's different.
You take Tommy.
Spare the rest.
You know,
my mother used to say this about you.
She said,
"That Polly Gray,
"that child would never
let go of a grievance."
And she loves to dance.
What do you say, huh?
You want to dance?
I don't dance any more.
Well, that's a shame.
'Cause you're dancing with me.
# On a gathering storm comes
a tall handsome man
# In a dusty black coat
with a red right hand #